check this before we've been live oh we
are public people might be watching cool
um so a solution raising is an hour long
conversation
we bring ourselves and our bias and
everything else to the conversation so
all of your experience everything that
you bring but the idea is to generate
something
new not necessarily hold on to something
we had before coming to the conversation
so this is to run parallel to the
conversation game b
had last week although both of you
attended you're
welcome to bring what was what happened
there into the conversation
but it isn't i wasn't there so i can't
build on what was done there it's like
parallel that anyone can watch it and
decide
what they want to get out of mapping
game b this
issue has come up consistently in game b
is how do you map it how does somebody
new understand
it how does so this is the first time
we've done a solution on game b
specifically where people who aren't
game b
wouldn't be able to really participate
so we spend 15 minutes talking about
what's currently being done
15 minutes talking about what we would
like in an ideal version of the future
and then we spend half
an hour usually talking about what we
could do with 10 000 people and 100 000
for this particular solution raising
because again he doesn't have 10 000
people
and we're focusing on game b i'm gonna
say with a thousand people
and ten thousand dollars but also with
the
ingenuity that's in game b right i think
there are people who are willing to do
some of the labor for free
so we don't need to have a hundred
thousand dollars so i'm just changing
the parameters so it's something that
could happen in game b
because again we don't have 10 000
people and we could still stick with a
hundred thousand dollars but then it
would be everyone putting in a hundred
dollars which i think is a little
we'll play with that when we get there
so for the first part we're talking
about
what is current what is g mapping and
game b currently look like
and why it keeps being a topic that we
need we need to talk about so
um we can each take a turn to share or
you can pass if you don't want to share
for that
for that portion then we can have an
open discussion for the remainder of
that
that time and then when it feels right
transfer on to the next part of the
conversation
so again the first 15 minutes or rather
10 minutes about we'll be talking about
what is currently being done to math
game b
and why we feel we need something
different
currently what's good and bad about
what's being done
either of you would like to start since
i wasn't there last week i don't
actually know what's currently being
done i'm just gonna talk to
okay so what is currently being done i
am
to be honest not sure apart from
adriel's
quick project um
list application but apart from that
i did not um find
any specific like uh
encompassing encompassing library or
catalog
of projects groups individuals
and i understand that it's because
um first there's no clear definition of
what game b
is and what criteria there are
for defining and determining if
something is game b or is something
between
a name a game b and
yeah there's that and
um and
yeah we as much as we don't want to
define it and
write in stone what exactly we are
looking for
and uh what exactly is game b
in uh i guess the concern
um there are many concerns about it so
we don't want this
but at the same time the projects that
are
out there are real and you would very
much like to know about them
and have some sort of um
like overview maybe not necessarily
uh of um
like everything from a specific angle
but more like
uh we would like to know what is out
there
in very general terms so
what has currently been done i know of
several
projects that are in beta stage
um to be said that there are many people
working on this
and i did see uh
along those years few
designs of few descriptions of what such
a system would look like
but as i am aware there is nothing
written
yet so
james do you want to share right um
so yeah i probably i feel like i'm also
not aware of probably a lot of the stuff
that's going on related to mapping
at the moment but there does seem to be
quite a lot of it popping up
and it was yeah it was really
interesting in the call last week to see
some of the projects actually kind of
connected to the game b space who are
working on
different tools that are kind of related
to the subject of mapping
so one example is a group called the
brain
and just to clarify this because it can
be confusing there's actually two
different mind mapping tools called the
brain but they're both spelled slightly
differently
um the original one is spelt like the
the normal way you'd spell the brain and
the new one uh which is the guys who are
involved with game b
it's spelt like uh b-r-a-n-e
like like membrane or something um
and yeah they're doing some really
interesting work um
there's also some some interesting
people who kind of came along who've
just been
involved in my mapping for a long time
um
using for example like the old version
of the brain
and tools like kumu um to kind of plot
out
you know just even just from a kind of a
personal perspective just to map out the
different
things that they're interested in their
life to kind of keep track of stuff
different links that they come across
different projects they're interested in
and to kind of organize it in a
framework that makes it easy for them to
then go and find that information
and navigate through it um so yeah
there's a lot of people that kind of
have an interest in this subject it
seems
and there's there's definitely projects
kind of moving uh
pushing the ball forward uh in that
space
um for me i would say like
the value of mapping is that it's uh
it's actually relevant to a lot of
different areas
so whenever you have a situation where
there's a landscape of some kind that's
that's very complex
and filled with lots of different data
and you're trying to make sense of that
uh what i think of the value of a map is
that it kind of takes all that
complexity
and reduces it down to a simple model
that's much easier to comprehend and has
the kind of key
bits of information that you need to be
able to navigate that landscape
so that could be you know in a really
basic sense that could be a physical
landscape
with just like a you know a paper map
that visualizes where the mountains are
and the villages and the roads
or it could be you know mapping
something
a bit more ephemeral like a social
network
and visualizing um different communities
and different types of connections
within that space that
if you didn't have a map to visualize
that would be very difficult to pick up
on
um and especially to kind of navigate
through so i think there's there's a lot
of value
in maps for that kind of reason
but to me and this is what i was kind of
bringing up in the call last week
what i'm most excited about with mapping
is
how it can be how people can collaborate
around shared maps
um because i think like part of the way
that our brains work is that we
the way we understand reality in the
world around us is that we
we build maps out of the information
that we we take in we kind of build
models within our minds so we're already
i think
naturally wired to be able to build maps
and to do that in a very kind of dynamic
flexible way
but i think what we lack at the moment
is the ability to
to build maps in that same kind of way
but collectively
in large groups that are often dispersed
you know across huge distances
so i think that's where the real
potential lies in the future is if we
can kind of develop tools that enable
groups
that are coordinating around any
different subject to be able to kind of
come together
and add their little pieces of data that
they each have from their perspectives
and have that kind of synthesized in a
shared map
that takes in all that information and
provides something that's very useful to
everyone
in terms of kind of coordinating finding
out what's going on
and knowing where to add their
contributions
so to me it's like a there's a real
exciting potential there to level up
uh group collective intelligence through
designing the right tools
thank you i will try to take only a
couple minutes to do
to do mine that the game b space is
very interesting to map because one we
don't even know what game b
is we don't know where we're going we
don't know how we transition to it we
don't
we there's many people who have ideas on
how we do that but
mapping those and figuring out how do
you do your individual piece to make
sense
but in doing so not like i want my sense
to add to the sense making
of the group not dissipate it and right
now because there's so many people come
into the games
be space and they're confused what's
going on what is game b
it's like we can't even answer that
question let alone what is happening
here who's involved what are the
projects
and so there's a handful of tools what
is game b
for some of us it's the conversation for
some of us it's the personal work for
some of us it's the project work and i
think it's all of the above
so to be able to have somebody come and
be new and be like right where's the gas
station you need to pull up the map and
say here's where we are and here's where
we need to go
and because we don't have that we don't
really
i think we need to take a step back and
brainstorm what we would want
mapped before we ever map and the per
the problem is everyone's writing their
own map and it's never really going to
be able to be used by somebody else
because we orient differently there is
no north south east west
here's the gas station and here's here's
how you get there
it's well my version of game b is this
we do this with currency and this with
governance and it's okay if yours is
different but we're going towards that
and what is the next step
and so having the conversation like i
was just writing down here
in the game b space the game be facebook
groups there's
already three that really are mapping
there's there's game b
wiki which is dealing with all the same
things but it kind of came to a stand
still because
the idea of the wiki is that it does all
this stuff right it's the tools it tells
us what projects it tells us with people
there's together tech which i'm involved
in
is is involved in of okay so we're
bringing our projects together and
figuring out
how can we create omni and solutions for
our project so they can get out in the
world
but the same issues keep coming up of
how do you know what's going on how do
you understand what game b is and i
think it isn't one document
it is a bunch of kind of understanding
of definitions and there's multiple
definitions for each word and multiple
courses and to honor and truly get that
there's complexity and no single map
can actually be the full thing and so
there's going to be things
other people have on their map that you
don't have on yours because you don't
care about gas stations you don't drive
right and there's other things that
we're going to have that are common and
so that to me is right now it feels
confusing to be a new person in game b
even not being a new person in game b
like when you come in it's like well
what's going on where can i be what can
what is what conversations can i attend
what conversations can i watch
what projects can i be part of how do i
create a project
how do we create a project together how
do we work through even not being
together
right and so this is a very fertile
ground
for complexity and mapping complexity
and working through this as a group
and having it be that there's all this
different stuff happening like there's i
was gonna say
there's the wiki there's the newer
mapping facebook
group and there's also technology tools
which are kind of
looking at what's already out there that
we can use in game b
but i feel like they come up constantly
right like the conversation generator
and then scheduling app and there's
certain things that are tools that a few
people and to try to understand what
projects are happening and what people
and mapping that
and it feels like we never get beyond
beta
because there's so many betas like it's
like none of them
are the thing and i don't know if many
people are mapping but there's a ton of
people who have
a project of projects janelle has one i
can never remember the name of
praxium no i think that's kylie's one um
and so there's all of these
different somewhat competing things and
none of them have have resources or the
like and this is a good transition to
the next part of the topic which is what
do we want it to look like and our idea
version of the future if we came
together and truly mapped game b
whatever that means to us as an
individual
what does that look like to us and this
portion
of the conversation doesn't need to
match it's not a democracy if james's
version of a map looks different than
two says looks different than mine
that's totally fine
it's what could it look like right it's
the elephant we're all feeling different
pieces and instead of arguing about
which one's right it's like putting
those pieces together to get the
elephant
is this for this solution raising even
more so than the rest so
whoever would like to share their
version of what their ideal
version of mapping game b looks like in
the future whether that's
tomorrow or five years from now
welcome i think
i like what you said like i think a
really key part of
it is that when people come to game b
just having a very
clear road map of like how to find their
way to what's going on
um so that they can actually yeah find
their way into these different subjects
and if they've got a
you know if they've got some kind of gem
that they've got to give just making
sure that it's very easy for them to
find
where the most appropriate place for
that is to be shared
um and i've just noted down here a
couple things like
to me an ideal map would would
uh one aspect would be that it's kind of
fractal so
you could have this kind of high level
map that takes you to the main sections
of game b
then as you navigate down to those areas
it's like a fractal and you could kind
of go down to smaller
smaller and smaller details um
so i think in that sense you could
actually have a single
overarching map that kind of integrates
all the different
smaller and smaller areas that you could
find within game b
um another aspect of it for me that i
think would be really key
is is making it as flexible as possible
so
kind of going back to your point that
you know if if we're each keep creating
kind of separate maps but they're
very much like customized to our
preferences then their their value to
other people is going to be quite
limited
so if we can create maps that um have
to give users the ability to kind of
customize how they're viewed
so that they can kind of they can
highlight different aspects of the map
maybe that they're interested in
um and you know even down to things like
potentially even customizing the ui so
they can actually
see it in a different way i think that
would
make it more accessible to a wider range
of people um
see those two aspects come to mind
it's hard to tell what should be on the
map because
because we are not uh 100
sure uh what it is we are mapping
so i also wanted to point out that
it is important what we don't map
and what we leave out of the big picture
one thing could be um
okay um what i wanted what i
thought it could start with
in the most simple way
so users who are new to the space are
not lost immediately
in the you know forest of ideas
ideologies
and high level uh
descriptions of what is wrong with game
a and what needs to be done
like uh for example um
many people who come to the space
do come here because they
perceive something being wrong with
capitalism and they are very anti
something
so they would expect a map of tools to
destroy
some economic system as they see being
not
fit to rule the world and it's not very
good
so if i wanted to start small
i would start with a set of well-defined
problems
that can be
ascribed to like old can be viewed as
game b solutions or ideas but at the
same time
not necessarily need uh this whole
concept of the mb being present at all
like for example we know that food and
water are problematic especially in
certain parts of the world
so if um there was a webpage
describing various ideas about how to
clean water that would be
game b on one hand as we
see game b but on the other hand for
someone who is new
they would see okay this is a solution
for one particular problem
that we can all agree that it is a
problem it is real
and it can be dealt with
um in local communities
in open source way and generally
um yeah
like using non-game a
solutions and ways of dealing with
problems so
that would be one thing and then um it
could be
that there are just few groups of
problems
that we need to deal with and
um like i said something like before
the bottom of uh muscle of pyramid
food water shelter communication
electricity like power
stuff like that and they all have their
own
defined uh sets of sub problems
and it all can fractally
expand from like okay we need there's
problem with uh
power as in electricity and
um then there are solutions and uh
it would just open like a tree like
not flower tree and
it could be visualized uh
in of course 3d space as we discussed on
this big
big uh meeting about mapping
and uh yeah the brain one
or the other and add various other
solutions that deal with mapping
uh they will be very useful in this in
this area uh but they are not complete
enough to
uh to be sufficient uh to
like not only visualize everything but
only
have additional um okay i'm getting
ahead of myself i think
uh technical um details not needed
at this point so yeah flattery
tree like structure that's what i would
like to see and that
is what would be the least confusing to
new people
because it would start with okay the
problem is water and
solutions abcd uh
and then each of the solutions would
have
their own set of like two more and more
detailed way of uh describing
in my ideal world is the technology
cooperative
it is not known by game b but game b
gave me the language around it
it's having somebody be able to come in
have their own individual unique map
based on who they are where can they
find their most
where can they find their teams of
people how can they find what projects
would most be useful for them both that
they would get
the most benefit being on that team and
also the team would must be able to use
them
um what i was sitting here drawing was
this idea between
its map so having where we are
we might be in conflict with but that
we're starting somewhere and we're
trying to understand this thing called
capitalism this thing called game a this
thing called history
and we might absolutely differ on what's
broken about what right now but that's
okay
we also might differ on what game b
actually is what does constitute game be
i think it's all of these interlocking
circles
that are different depending on who you
are so for me it's omni-win solutions
it's it's concentrated on the
anti-rivalry solutions that actually
getting better the more people are
involved in scalability and being a
natural attractor and out-competing game
a
and it's in its own its own field for
other people it's not all it's
part of that but not all of that and so
for me game b is kind of the
sweet spot of long my bend diagrams but
really game b is
is all of our interconnecting circles
together and showcasing that i like what
james had to say that
having to be individualistic the ui
being what i see can be in development
individualized to me but understanding
the complexity
i don't know almost like a choose your
own adventure like here's how where i
think we're broken
right like like my version of the map
would be where we're starting where i
want to get to
and then the many different paths that
could get us there
it's somehow mapping that so that the
individual has access to their
best information about where we are and
how they understand it their best
version of this this idea in the future
of this ideal world we're never going to
get to because
utopias aren't possible because you're
you're maximizing it for your values
the path to getting there is like this
magical just everyone having that vision
and starting from where they are instead
of arguing about where we start and
where we get to we just start moving
it actually weaves together to be game b
but that only showcases in the doing of
it it is the
different people working on different
projects and figuring out the the
fracturedness of it
that isn't fractal it's fractured and
then making the fractured fractal
and constantly be instead of it being
everyone's dissipated
hey why do you feel that you don't
understand
what's going on what would make it make
sense to you like having the feedback in
it
for what's not working so it continually
be improved for everybody
and i think that is a bit of what mine
would
look like that's the best summary i
heard about
uh game b space which is making the
fractured fractal
this is exactly what it is about it
i was like yeah there's something about
the fractal and the fracture yeah
yeah because now we have all these
shards of
goodwill energy skills and everything
they are just not connected so
the way i see this this project it would
be not even
well there are so many different aspects
of this that
one meeting is not going to cover even a
small amount of it
but uh in short uh there's not only the
mapping aspect
uh the knowledge of what's out there
there is the connectivity aspect as well
there is this
uh enabling that this talking to
everyone involved who might be involved
would like to be involved and yeah
it's a lot of work very exciting
yeah but i think there is ways like we
because it hasn't been done before
we look at it like that's a chaotic mess
that can never kind of
happen like these conversations never
happened until they did right
we're able to come up with a possible
adjacent possible that we could create
right now with ten thousand people at a
hundred thousand dollars
just having the conversation showcasing
it's possible right like once you're
able to run is it the five-minute mile
then everyone was not everyone but a lot
of people were able to break five in a
mile
that having people showcase what is
possible
creates the idea that's possible because
game b is complex right having everyone
have food everyone have water everyone
have electricity everyone have these
omnium solutions
we have different ideas on how to get
there yet i do think we have a co
fairly common if if we had let's say 100
game b people
brainstorm what are all the things that
would need to be in place for you to be
living your game be
we would see that although none of us
have exactly the same
we all have very common overlapping ones
like having a tool to assess how do we
get water how do we get food
the best way for ourselves right having
their
information that's accessible and usable
on you know if we're going through
pandemic oven 19 but like on climate
change on healthcare on anything that
you're dealing with having information
that's usable and accessible
and so breaking it down in that way so
we can see the problem
and then how many people are working on
solutions and
what solution offers what and can we you
know combine them and just
mapping that mapping where we are and
how we get to
our version of game b gets us all the
game because my version might not
include feeding the world
it does but i don't know why it wouldn't
but right i might think it's less
important
to educate the world i want everyone to
have access to everything but
i'm a weirdo that way it's like active
mapping
it's not only knowledge but it's only
all also
connectivity and i think it's a it's
common mistake to
um and it's very game a to think that uh
everyone sorry i'm connecting to some
other piece of information
uh should follow the same manifesto or
the same set of values
everyone is in game game be actually
expected to
uh do their own thing by their own
rules to some extent uh maybe
on a foundation of the same set of
values more or less because
the higher order values seem to be very
similar between people like all over the
world
um but yeah by doing their own thing
uh feeling uh the own like niche
of like i want to be doing this so i'm
doing this and
somehow magically it is connected with
every every scene
else that is going on and everyone
uh what everyone else is doing that by
doing their
own thing they just create everyone is
creating the game
so what we need is a like a platform
it's like
um in a forest that trees like lots of
trees
and uh on the surface like they are not
connected
maybe they are but you know but
underneath the surface
uh there is this whole like mycelium
thing going on
and there's vast networks of information
and value exchange
that can cover like square miles
and i i see the platform being something
like something like this
connecting providing a communication
means of
means of coordination and cooperation
something like this
in the most agnostic way possible
like no ideology no
enforcing a specific set of
views or values it's not what it's for
it's only for making cooperation and
communication possible
yeah i think that is actually the side
that for some reason
because mapping where we are and where
we need to get to and how we get there
is very different for every individual
and so
is sorry i lost my train of thought are
you just saying
having the tools i don't remember
it was great though if it's not it's
gone wouldn't it either it'll be back if
it's meant to
it'll be back that was making me think
that actually
um what you're saying which is that one
value of mapping
is that it can can enable it can be a
framework that enables people to all be
acting at their kind of individual level
doing that the things that they're
interested in
and yet somehow weave those
contributions together so that you get
something
emerging at the collective level that
couldn't be achieved by any of the
individuals alone and they may not even
be
aware of what that bigger picture is
going to be but by having
the right kind of tools and framework it
can actually weave
all these different contributions
together so i think it can be a very
like
integrating process and i i it's like
the um the analogy of like similarities
to actually the way our brain works
in that you know we build very complex
models of the world around us
and you know a single neuron is not able
to hold
the fullness of one of those models it's
only through coordinating those neurons
very effectively that you get this
capacity to build
complex models that transcend by a long
way the capabilities of any individual
neurons
so i think that's my kind of like one of
my dreams with mapping is that you know
if we can if we can work out the
dynamics and we can build those kind of
basic tools
obviously it's going to start small and
they'll probably be a long period where
it's being tested and refined but once
we get that capacity it's it's there
isn't really any scale
limits and it could be one of those kind
of game b technologies where
actually the more people that
participate the um the value goes up
rather than down so you can actually you
know at global scale suddenly you could
have
incredibly uh complex things being
mapped a very quick speed
um just by having the right tool that
everyone could log on online can kind of
explore the map that's that's been
created already they can find the areas
that where there's blind spots in the
map they can add their little
contributions
and everyone's doing this simultaneously
you just get this this complex landscape
mapped very quickly
through everyone's collaboration
yeah i love that and i remember the
thought which was
to what what you should said and do not
to deal with this is individuals right
we're individuals living our lives so
what does it look like as an individual
as jubilee how do i have as much
as much sovereignty as possible the
irony is there's only so much i can do
by myself in sovereignty
there's a certain amount that we have to
do collectively like if i'm fed and
housed and clothed
i have more sovereignty to not rely on
my government to not rely on outside
forces
and so keep owning that and looking for
places to from our celebrity and then in
groups
looking at okay how does this group have
sovereignty how do we decide on a
collective governance and then have the
bigger
group the group of groups to not how
how little authority do they have on the
teams and the individuals right
because we are the ones making it up and
there's this difference
that i'm exploring in my own life like
the war versus the dance and i know
sometimes i'm in war with people that i
want them to do what i want them to do
because of the outcome
right i want people to stay at home
right now how dare you go out this is my
but it's like it's they're not doing it
to spite me and they're doing it for
their own
their own best interest if i'm needing
to be in control over someone's life
even though i course i don't have
control over their life but my
bean wants to be in control of them
right i want like new
governing rules that will get you to
behave in the way i want you to behave
instead of how do i behave in the way i
want to behave and how do we create
a society that if there is a good way to
be it
enables people to be that way instead of
enforcing it and that is very again the
individualistic like what is my map and
how do i increase my sovereignty how do
i find my groups and how do i help other
people find their groups
and then how can the tools and the
technology facilitate that in the
process without ruling over it
right without saying you have to do x y
and z to be part of this to be part of a
group you might need to
but you could always find a different
group and there's
hopefully as few rules as possible over
the overarching
bigger meta group that is facilitated
yeah that actually reminded me of a
conversation i was having with
uh eric liberate mankind the other day
but we were talking about
he's got this concept of the monarchy he
calls it
which is kind of this kind of balance
between the monarchy which is kind of
the
um well i from my perspective i see it
as kind of like representing order
and then anarchy representing chaos
although it's i know the model is more
complicated than that
that kind of simplifies it down but um
one of the points that came up in the
conversation was that if you have
um you know in in kind of oppressive
dictatorships it actually takes an
enormous amount of energy
to force people to do things that they
don't naturally want to do
so if you can design a system that can
actually
coordinate people and kind of harness
them them doing the things that they
most enjoy you actually as a system
become capable of a huge amount more
with much less energy expenditure and
people
well so it's kind of like a win-win on
all dimensions
um and these these kind of systems that
try to kind of control populations
through like rigid
dictatorial laws and stuff it can only
work temporarily and it's very fragile
because
um yeah it's just people aren't happy
they're being forced to do what they
have to do
and that you have to employ and pay
people to enforce the other people and
it's just um
enormous waste of energy versus a system
that's able to coordinate people's
differences
and unique interests um so if we could
do that and maybe mapping can be a part
of that
just helping people you've got interests
find the place that they can
can contribute out to the collective
that's interesting on a scale
where on one extreme
there is a dictatorship very centralized
uh which is telling people exactly what
to do and how
and um steering uh
from central point like everything
people are unhappy
and motivation is very low and
the overall energy of the system is low
and it's a struggle to get anything done
definitely um
those systems tend to not last very long
or if they do it's it's costing like
enormous amount of blood basically
and then there are systems where uh
yeah it's like the free market metaphor
is
kind of appropriate here because what we
talked about
is kind of similar it takes the best of
the free market idea
which is everyone is doing their thing
and somehow magically it
produces like great results for everyone
which is not necessarily true uh
as we see in the world there is
something to it
but it's like the shadow of this idea
is also very strong and it's not being
talked too much about
uh yeah for whatever reason
uh the shadow being that the bottom line
is always
people are forced to do what
um to do something
they are free to choose what uh work
they do but they still need to do
something
um because of the dynamic of uh if i
don't work
i will not have any money and then i
will starve and
game over so there is that
and um if we took oh yeah and free
market is very
individualistic the basic uh thing about
free market is
everyone is like an individual and the
magic happens between
individuals on some higher level and
what we are talking about is
more like uh yes everyone is doing their
thing
but we also do the thing collectively
and we are able to recognize
the collectives we are in like local
communities local uh
local but interest groups and the
dynamic in those groups
uh is not based on just monetary
values not on money being past the scent
in any direction just
recognizing our best interest
is i think that the key here
so i'm just going to switch over to the
the next topic so you don't have much
time you usually have half an hour we
only have about 20 minutes to
to explore it of what could game b
actually create right now
if it had a thousand people like
dedicated to even just collecting their
data and be part of a conversation
and then what could those thousand
people create together if they
were able to volunteer let's say three
four hours a week
a month and then also ten thousand
dollars so you have those thousand
people putting in ten dollars and you
also have them contributing some of
their
their intellectual emotional physical
labor what could we create together and
of course everything's voluntary so
we're not like forcing a thousand people
to do that
what could be created that would entice
them would be a natural attractor
that game b could do that maybe isn't
individuals
working solely in their own their own
interests where that
is able to weave together to be the
collective collective benefits so if
anyone has any ideas on what we could do
as an adjacent possible for
a b mapping i will let you start
well i think there's actually already
some interesting things that are
happening
that wouldn't even necessarily need an
injection of cash that they're just
kind of naturally developing like the
brain project
where they've already got a kind of a
beta product
and they're developing it pretty quickly
they're hoping to have it live
so people can test it out fairly soon
i'm not sure what the exact date is
but part of their plan is to create a
questionnaire
which can be shared with the game b
community that would
ask a bunch of different questions and
they're actually i've got a call with
them tomorrow
and hunter to kind of discuss to talk
through what would
uh what good questions would be to ask
people but you know it could be things
like
um you know what what subjects do you
think are relevant to game a or game b
what things are you personally most
interested in which ones
do you think are most relevant versus
not relevant
and there's lots of different types of
questions that could gather up data from
the community
and then that could be kind of plotted
into a map graph type thing
where you know you've got all this data
suddenly represented in a way that
people can explore through it and they
can kind of find
different communities or they could find
people who are interested in different
things or they could
kind of get a sense of what the
collective perspective is of game b
um just through the way that data is
visualized
so i think stuff like that is actually
already just in the process of
developing
and i think in the next year we'll see a
few things like that starting to pop up
more
to me the thing that's most exciting
about it i guess if there was
you know more participation and this
kind of continued to develop in a
positive way
is that once we've got some of those
tools in place that it could actually
uh be beneficial to all the different
things that game b is doing
so you know gamey projects gamey online
tools
like all these different groups they all
share the same need to be able to
organize the content that they're doing
and allow people to find and explore
through that
so i think i see that as being like one
of the goals of gaming mapping is to
produce something that's actually useful
to
all the other groups and to game b
as a whole so it's kind of again yeah
like fractal in its potential uses
yeah 10 000 people can gets like produce
a lot of data which is like
two things one is gathering the data and
then uh processing and visualizing
the data and results so 10 000 people
could
could start immediately as soon as there
is some questionnaire uh
just fill it in and
see what happens then
yeah i think there's a lot of of stuff
that can be done and is being done in
this space for
less money than it would cost any
individual one to do or less it's just
about like not necessarily dissipating
the energy into eight different projects
and picking which one's the best and
focusing our energy there
like one of the things that we could do
is with a thousand people is do
something i had kind of
talked to when i first came into the
game b space when extinction rebellion
was talking about their citizen
assemblies and i was like
why do we want why are we out in the
streets protesting to get our
governments to instill citizen
assemblies
we're the citizens we can just hold
assemblies like we could just get those
people
you know gather the information on
climate change present it in a way that
it's understandable for us
like there's things we can do without
going through the government and doing
something similarly with the thousand
people
to so that it's different through time
zones have zoom
rooms and have it be that we've asked
these questions right instead of it just
being
a survey having conversations about what
does game b
mean to me what is game what is what are
the subject matters that i think
are important and then seeing the
interconnecting circle seeing where you
know
why history is important to me and it
doesn't matter if history is important
everyone else if it's important to me
how can i map that on to game b and how
can in reverse having one place we can
go to both input and get
the people involved in game b both the
the people actually involved right where
we're i'm a game b person
contact me right and then there's people
who maybe
aren't game b but they're game b
adjacent like jordan peterson i don't
think has maybe even heard about game b
but a lot of people follow him and
found through here right jordan hall
more and jim wrap more game b
they've identified themselves as game b
but they're also game b
adjacent in that people want to watch
all of their content right and do that
i think having a way to know who's been
on whose podcast and which ones are the
most important what they talk about
instead of kind of giving everybody
homework in the game space i can already
you first get here there's so many
podcasts so many just to catch up and
then
you realize you can't never are you
going to be able to watch all of jordan
hall stuff and all of jim rot stuff and
he can't even watch all my stuff and i'm
not even not
like it was just too many conversations
about participating in them
but having someone say hey watch this
and instead of
hey everybody watch this i'm able to
actually distill the points to you so
you don't need to watch it
and it's catalog so if we need the
relevant parts we can go to it and see
that
and have that be more more relevant to
both just
as people come into game b and feel lost
having a conversation with them three
four months old being like what is it
that you were looking for that we didn't
give you and then they're
instrumental in helping create that for
the next group of people right because
if what they were looking for was the
people and they weren't even
easily able to find them they can help
the next group of people find their
people
right so um i think using existing
technology that's already there like
zoom
and coordinating it so that we don't
need to create new
new technology yet until we have the
foundation of what it is we actually
would want in our gaming platform what
is
what are these overarching solutions of
food water clothing what's currently
being done to pick
what is the most powerful project we
could do
after conversation and then actually put
energy and time into creating that and
work through that process together
and even if it falls apart because it
might fall apart a lot of them have
fallen apart
is that we learn and if we do that
transparently we learning grow and it
learns and grows too
and literally start anywhere and keep
improving it
is is the solution to everything start
somewhere and keep improving it and do
so openly and transparent
that would be one of the questions on
the questionnaire uh about
game b and what to think about it and
what they
see like what uh how did you get here
that's the most obvious and then what
piece of information
you got was most uh
enlightening to you it's like which part
of usually there is this
um jordan greenhouse interview with
someone
and then in about nine ten minutes
in there is this piece about uh how to
solve
like the problem the problem of
cooperation and
uh incentivization i think it was uh
and it was so that was the part that
struck me as the
most important thing ever in in this
space
and if everyone said okay for me
it was this point for me it was this
interview and this part of it like
watch this five minutes and you'll get
more than if you watched
uh two hours of someone else's talking
which might be equally important but
then
the five minutes is what it is all about
something like this yeah
like mapping was already been done this
is like too much too much information
and knowing what conversations a big
proponent of conversations know what
conversations are going on when that
you're invited to
which ones can you watch all gym rat
stuff all jordan halls that's available
it's definitely there
but even in the conversation space in
the other spaces what's
what's there and i don't want to watch
hundreds and hundreds of hours i want to
know what is pertinent right if i'm i'm
looking at competition versus
um cooperation what are the top 10 talks
on that that i could watch for five
minutes
right one one might be jordan hall won't
be jordan peterson one might be eric
right like
it depends on who actually have the
conversation and people we can upload
them and
tag the videos right be like oh this is
a like the highlighting right
like this part is really cool and the
more we uploaded it
the more it would gain eyes instead of
just instead of
what i feel often happens in the game tv
space where people are giving each other
homework right everyone needs to read
this
everyone needs to watch this and like
there is no read what you're interested
in and then bring that to the
conversations that you're part of bring
that to the projects
but if we all have the same information
that's not very
sovereign that's not very like follow
your
interests and then bring those interests
to the
things that you're part of did you guys
see
by your chance did you see the uh the
tool that nick had been building where
you kind of you put in like a youtube
url and then it it scrapes through and
is able to kind of identify all the most
used words and it kind of represents
that on a graph did you guys see that
no i saw this like a screenshot of this
and i was most impressed yeah it's
really interesting
um but yeah to me that's just like a
taster of some of the things that we
could
nick nick red red marks name
yeah and i had no idea he was working on
stuff like that i'd seen him kind of
participating in game b and then that
popped up and i was like wow
oh that's amazing um but yeah that's
that's like a way of you know using
some software to kind of take a video
which would otherwise
you'd have to sit through the whole
thing or read a transcript but it just
instantly visualizes um the content of
that video
and like he's chosen a certain way to do
that but you could imagine all
different kinds of ways of visualizing
things that pick up on different kinds
of aspects of the video
so i think stuff like that's really cool
and then another thought i had was
um an idea i was thinking about a while
ago was
you know imagine if as you were
exploring through the different facebook
the game b facebook group or some of its
subgroups if you came across
a post or a comment even and you were
like oh that really links well with this
other post this other comment thread
that i saw the other day
if you could just kind of highlight both
of them somehow and draw a link between
them and describe that relationship and
then if you imagine
everyone was able to do this
simultaneously you could start building
up these kind of
networks between related content and i
feel like that's like another kind of
mapping
eu related uh concept that could allow
people to
to kind of help other people find stuff
and then also enable
each other to explore better you know if
you come across an interesting subject
you just you can see straight away that
there's links to other things that are
related to that so it's
it's easier for you to find um so yeah
that's something that's another cool
thing that i think could
i don't know exactly you know my views
are on this is that i don't think a lot
of these innovations are going to come
through facebook
or many of these dominant platforms so i
i still kind of think that we kind of
we need some other platform um
so i don't know how soon that's going to
happen but i can just see
all these different ideas and you know
there's so many people working on it it
just seems inevitable to me that at some
point we are going to make that leap and
it's just going to unlock
an enormous amount of um different
tools and features and enable us to kind
of uplevel our collective intelligence
such a huge amount machine learning
i would say uh could be very useful in
this respect because
as much as i trust people to find
links and connections that's what our
brains do
after all we are good at it not everyone
would
see the same connections but
collectively we can make something
beautiful
but uh if it could be helped with some
kind of machine learning
application whatever stuff and that for
example
uh the way i visualized it is
if i was if you were it was in the
middle of a graph
and i said okay i want to know more
about
governance on blockchain whatever
then uh around straight away
notes of a notes
pop up with most matching what i just
uh asked the system to tell me
and then uh by uh
kind of weighted proximity thing
uh i could i should be able to explore
further and further and the connections
would be
made by i think what nick
did something like this it would be a
basis for uh
either people doing the matching and
linking
um i think google algorithm works
in some similar way
page ranking all right
so yeah it can be done by a
computer to actually link everything and
show it
uh in the most matching document
to what you want to see is this
and then further the most matching
document to the document you just saw
is this and this and exploration um
like going on a fractal uh
tree and further away it would be
yeah something like this and yeah
yeah that would be that would be cool i
just wanna we only have about
less than five minutes left and so how
we end this is we go around and each
person can say what they think is
the solution we count with or you can
complicate in the moment that you think
is the most powerful
you think would be the most impactful or
solving what we are trying to solve
which today is mapping gaming
i guess for me it would be just creating
that kind of
the the most basic um
kind of mapping tool that's that's got
the most basic features required but
it's enough to enable
mapping of all different kinds of
subjects and doing it collaboratively
it sounds like a very complicated thing
but i actually think you could reduce it
down to a pretty simple set of rules
and dynamics it just needs to be really
well thought through
um and have a nice ui to kind of match
with that
but i think if we were able to do that
in a very basic level which
i just think it could be applied in all
these different areas
and different scales as well so i think
if we could nail that initial design
i think that's it could grow into a kind
of an unlimited
tree of other different things
yeah i totally agree uh starting small
with something very simple because the
yeah most
important thing is to just start even
if it was a system with one text
box with enabling people to write down
stuff and then connect it to some other
stuff
there will be a start and that would be
where data
starts being gathered and then it can be
always improved
instead of designing a perfect system
from scratch and
you know just start actually
i really like the work that you've been
doing that you demoed to us
in the call i think it was on thursday
so
remember with the lines and stuff yeah i
thought that was really cool
are you still working yes yes
furiously oh yeah
if you want to chat about it some other
time yeah it's it sounds like he's very
fine with some of my ideas um as well so
jubilee by the way this is what i wanted
to show you on
our last meeting uh which didn't work
because i
couldn't screenshare but
yes that's something um and
yeah it started very long time ago with
me
wanting to do some something that i no
longer want to do but
still i have this idea in my head that
it needs to be expressed
sometimes there are ideas that um
yeah i have this sorry to take up time
with this but
i had something like uh there are
certain ideas that want to express
themselves and they use humans as a
vehicle of um enacting this
this idea so that's i had it stuck in my
head and
i just need to uh finish it
and i am totally definitely happy to uh
use that as some kind of well
to show it more to work on this and it
to be
a foundation of some useful tool at
least
that would be perfect
because as much as i um in the
last few weeks i
watched most of the tools out there
the mapping tools uh including the brain
the seven vortex thing is also very cool
then the hollow web is also it's
beautiful
but each of them is um
[Music]
i didn't think uh of any of them that
this is the perfect thing
and all of them are missing
uh like some part of some aspect and
obviously uh the least we can do
like the modest thing to do is to
make a tool that does it all
so yeah i love it because while i was
writing down mine you gave me a piece of
it
so i think although i didn't really talk
about it during our solutions one of
it's one of the tools that in common
would help with all of the solutions
um as well as like feeding ourselves and
getting that stuff ready so we have more
sovereignty
that's harder to do having a like a yelp
of apps that we own together that we can
trust when someone works for a tool and
it's available that you know it exists
but what i love that you gave me
is like part of knowing what one feature
has another feature has that was
definitely
to know which one to use right of all
the team building ones which one's the
best
but to be able to actually say what's
missing why don't i use this one because
then we can kind of create one that's
the best of all worlds right like
what is facebook missing a lot but like
that you actually articulate it right
that the other ones have
and to be able to see when nick creates
something when matu creates so anyone
creates something in or out of game b
that it's then able to be available to
the world in a way that goes
around facebook and google right that's
like hey we know it exists
is it trustworthy does it work and then
how can we improve it even
whether we own it together or somebody
else owns it how can we actually
continually improve this so we can trust
it more so it gets to be the best of
both worlds right it gets to have all
the features that we would need it to
have
and at a price point we can afford which
hopefully is zero
you know like the app can sustain itself
the people can sustain itself but the
people using it have as little
input as possible because it's
anti-rivalrous and the more they're
involved in it the better benefit there
is for everyone
but we are definitely at the hour mark
does anyone have any closing statements
before
go jump on the discord call
[Music]
all right thank you james and josh